live.
>> Welcome to the Israel of God question
and answer
where we answer your questions according
to the Bible. Uh we're opening up with
the Ten Commandments that God commanded
the world to keep. Brother Tanzel.
>> And God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which hath brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shall have no
other gods before me. Thou shalt not
make unto thee any graven image, or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. Why the Lord thy God am
a jealous God, visiting the iniquities
of the fathers upon the children, unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me, and showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me, and keep
my commandments. Thou shalt not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain. For
the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain. Remember
the Sabbath day to keep it holy. Six
days shall thy labor and do all thy
work. But the seventh day is the Sabbath
of the Lord thy God. And in it thou
shall not do any work. Thou nor thy son,
nor thy daughter, thy man's servant, nor
that maid servant, nor thy cattle, nor
thy stranger that is within thy gates.
For in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day, and
hollowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shall not kill. Thou shall
not commit adultery. Thou shall not
steal. Thou shall not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shall not
cover thy neighbor's house. Thou shall
not cover thy neighbor's wife, nor his
man's servant, nor his maid servant, nor
his ox, nor his ass, nor anything that
is thy neighbors. We we read Exodus 20
1-1 17. And may the Lord have a blessing
to the reading of his words. In Jesus
name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> So here, Amen. And so here on question
and answer, we answer your questions
according to the Bible. We ask that you
uh submit your questions and we will
answer them in the order that they were
given. And uh let me introduce you
tonight to those that are on the panel.
We got brother Julius.
>> Good evening everybody.
>> We got brother Jerome.
>> Race and peace.
>> We got brother Tanzel.
>> Good evening everyone. We got brother
Sean.
>> Good evening.
>> We got sister Deborah.
>> We got the guest caller and my name is
an brother Dre. And we will get started
with our first question of the evening.
What's our first question, Sister
Deborah?
>> Uh, yes. There are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. Uh
Detroit Troy Price asks in Ezekiel 16
47 and 48,
why is Samaria and Sodom referred to as
the sisters of Israel?
>> Um we're going to ask brother Julius to
answer that question. Brother Julius,
>> good evening everybody. Samaria is
Israel. It's just the northern part of
Israel. Judah is the southern part of
Israel. Why is Samaria and Sodom
referred to as sisters to of Israel? And
because of Israel, Israel's very poor uh
behavior toward the Lord God of Israel.
And let's go to that Ezekiel 16. Tenzel,
when you get it, let's read verse 45.
Let's get an answer to this right here.
Begin at verse 45. Ezekiel 16:45.
Look what look what the Lord said about
Israel. Go ahead.
>> Thou art thy mother's daughter that
loaded her husband and her children.
Thou are the sister of thy sisters which
loaded their husband and their children.
Your mother was an Hitittite and your
fathers an Amorite.
>> Uhhuh. Because you got us out of those
out of the land of from among the
Canaanites. Go ahead. Go ahead.
>> And thy elder sister is Samaria. She and
her daughters that dwell at thy left
hand, and thy younger sister that
dwelleth at that right hand.
>> Yes, go ahead.
>> It's Sodom and her daughters. But yet
thou not walked after their ways, nor
done after their abominations. But if
that were a very little thing, thou as
But as if it were,
>> Start the top of that 47 again. But but
yet hast thou not walked after their
ways, nor done after their abomination.
But as if that were a very little thing,
thou was corrupted more than they in all
thy ways.
>> By turning from the two of living God,
they God were no God, but our God, we
turned from him, and we walked in the
ways of these nation that he took us out
of. Go ahead at 48.
>> As I live, sayeth the Lord God, Sodom,
thy sister have not done. She know her
daughters as thou has done thou and thy
daughters.
>> One more verse.
>> Behold, this was the iniquities of thy
sister. Sodom pride, fullness of bread,
and abundance of idleness was in her and
in her daughters. Neither did she
straighten the hand of the poor and
needy.
>> So, this was Israel's very poor behavior
toward one another and and toward the um
God of Israel. And the Lord said, "Don't
learn the cursing of the nations that I
cast out before you, which I uh gave you
their land, and now you doing just like
them." And that's why the Lord compared
Solomon, Israel. One more place. Let's
go to Romans 9. Look what Paul said. And
Paul is quoting Isaiah 1 and9. Romans
9:10 and just one verse 29.
It was a we did some abominable things
against our God. 9 and 29. Go ahead and
read.
>> And as Isaiah said before, except the
Lord of Sabbat have left us a seed, we
had been as Sodom and been made like
unto Gomorrah.
>> And the Lord compared our behavior to
Sodom and Gomorrah. And you know what he
did? He destroyed Sodom and Gomorrah for
their uh for their abominations which
they exceeded uh the wicked
abominations. So the Lord destroyed
Sodom and Gomorrah. The Lord said, "Hey,
he married us." He didn't know them
other nation. They didn't know the Lord,
but he married us and gave us good law,
statutes, and commandment, and we
violated. That's what he compared us to
them people like that. And if it wasn't
for the Lord, the covenant that he made
with Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob, we
wouldn't exist as a nation. That's all I
got. Dre,
>> thank you, brother Julius, for that
answer. Sister Deborah, what's our next
question?
>> Yes. TB asks, "Who will be in the
wilderness during the three and a half
year?" Excuse me. Who will be teaching
in the wilderness during the three and a
half years before the return of Christ?
>> We're going to ask the guest caller to
answer that question. Guest caller.
>> But I can't answer something that's not
in the book.
Most of the people that go into the
wilderness for the great tribulation,
most of those people will be informed
and taught already.
But if there is any teaching to be going
on during that time, the book don't say,
so we don't know.
>> Thank you for that guest caller. We're
going to move on, Sister Deborah, to our
next question.
>> Yes. Moving on. Kaylee Parker asks,
"What does Exodus 22 28 and 29 mean in
its entirety?"
Uh, and are the firstborns given as
sacrifice in this verse?
>> We're going to ask brother Jerome to
answer that question. Brother Jerome,
uh,
>> let's go read the verses. Uh, Exodus 22
verse 28 and 29.
Get it? Go ahead. Read.
>> Thou shall not revile the gods, nor
curse the rulers of thy people. Thou
shall not delay to offer the first of
thy right fruits and of thy liquor. The
firstborn of thy son shalt thou give
unto me.
>> Okay. Um I'm going have to divide these
verses up to answer. Um let's deal with
verse 28
um first and then we'll come back to 29.
Um let's go to Romans the 13th chapter
verse 1 through 4.
Uh it'll shed some light on what he's
referring to in this 28 verse when he
said revile the gods.
uh
Romans 13
and read verse 1-4.
You get go ahead and read.
>> Let every soul be subject to the higher
powers. But there is no power but of
God, and the powers that be are ordained
of God.
But whosoever therefore resists the
power resists the ordinance of God, and
they that resist shall receive to
themselves damnation.
For rulers are not a terror to good
works, but to the evil. With thou then
be not without thou then not be afraid
of the power. Do that which is good, and
thou shalt have praise of the same. For
he is the minister of God to thee for
good. But if thou do that which is evil,
be afraid, for he beareth not the sword
in vain. For he is the minister of God,
a revenger to execute wrath upon him
that doeth evil.
>> Yeah. So when he's talking about revile
not the gods, he he talking about the
the uh the power the higher powers that
are ordained of God.
Okay. So um can let's go back to that um
Exodus 22 and read that verse 29 again.
Thou shall not delay to offer thy first
of thy ripe fruits and of thy liquor.
The firstborn of thy son shalt thou give
unto me.
>> Okay. Now
to address the first of the first ripe
fruit, let's go to Deuteronomy 26
and read verse 1-4.
>> Deuteronomy 26.
>> Yeah. Deuteronomy 26 verse
1-4.
Let me get it. Go ahead and read.
>> And it shall be when thou are come in
into the land which the Lord thy God
giveth thee for inheritance, and possess
it, and dwellest therein,
that thou shalt take of the first of all
the fruit of the earth, which thou shalt
bring of thy land that the Lord thy God
giveth thee, and thou shalt put it in a
basket, and shall go unto the place
which the Lord thy God shall choose to
place his name there. And thou shalt go
unto the priest that that shall be in
those days, and say unto him, I profess
this day unto the Lord thy God, that I
am come unto the country which the Lord
swear unto our fathers for to give us,
and the priest shall take the basket out
of thy hand, and set it down before the
altar of the Lord thy God.
>> That's good. That's good. So it's, you
know, it's talking about when Israel
come into their land
and
he don't want you to delay the offer the
first of the ripe your your white fruit
and liquor. Okay? Uh
and there's another part that that's in
that verse 29 that talked about uh the
firstborn of the son shall thou give.
He not actually talking about
sacrificing them like the priest did
with the animals. He talking about
offering and the offering the uh the
best answer we can give to address that
will be in numbers. So let's go to
numbers
the eth chapter
and we going to read verse 10 and 11. We
going to skip.
So you talking about making an offering
with with the sons, not the actual not
to sacrifice them. Okay?
When you get it, read verse 10 and 11.
We going to skip numbers 8 verse 10 and
11.
Go ahead.
>> And thou shall bring the Levites before
the Lord. And the children of Israel
shall put their hands upon the Levites.
And Aaron shall offer the Levites before
the Lord for an offering of the children
of Israel that they might execute the
servants of the Lord.
>> Yeah. See, this is not a sacrifice. It's
a offering. All right. Because the Lord
got a service for the Levites. But he
ain't just talking about the Levites.
And we going to keep reading. He going
to deal with the nation of Israel, too.
Keep read. Skip. Actually, skip down to
verse 16 and 17.
Mhm.
>> For they are holy, given unto me from
among the children of Israel, instead of
such as open every womb, even instead of
the firstborn of all the children of
Israel have I taken them unto me.
All the firstborn of the children of
Israel are mine, both man and beasts. On
the day that I smoke every firstborn in
the land of Egypt, I sanctified them for
myself.
>> Yeah. Because remember when they came
out of Egypt, the Lord slayed all the
firstborn of the Egyptians. It wasn't a
house among the Egyptian where there
wasn't one dead among the firstborn.
>> But Israel, they did what the Lord said
and put themselves under the blood
during that Passover and they firstborn
was spared. So he said the f all the
firstborn is mine.
>> Right.
>> Especially among the children of Israel.
>> That's right.
>> Yeah. Uh, that's all I got on it.
>> Thank you, brother Jerome, for that
answer.
Sister Deborah, we'll go to our next
question.
>> Yes. Moving on. Zion says, "I'm going
through so much in my life. I tried to
keep the laws, but nothing ever works
out." People says, "It's because I don't
attend church." Those same people don't
keep one commandment, but are thriving.
Why?
>> It's a great question. Uh let's go to uh
Psalm 73.
Psalm 73 and we going to read verses 1
to3 and we'll skip from there.
>> Psalm 73 1:3.
Go ahead, brother. When you get it,
Tanzel,
>> truly God is good to Israel, even to
such as are of a clean heart. But as for
me, my feet were almost gone. My steps
had well not slipped. For I was envious
at the foolish when I saw the prosperity
of the wicked.
>> Yeah.
>> Hold on. So skip down now to verse five
and read five and six. Go ahead.
>> They are not in trouble as other men,
neither are they plagued like other men.
Therefore pride can passeth them about
as a chain. Bodies cover them as a
garment.
>> So
we talking about the wicked and they
prospering and they got pride
and this brother is envious at them. Now
skip down and read verse 12. Go ahead.
>> Behold these are the ungodly who prosper
in the world. They increase in riches.
>> Yes sir. Now skip down and read verses
16 and 17.
>> When I thought to know this, it was too
painful for me until I went into the
sanctuary of God. Then understood I
therein.
>> Now see this is the this is the key
here. You said you said in your question
that I'm going through so much and I try
to keep the laws but nothing works out.
People say it's because I don't attend
church. But this brother had the same
feelings you had. And when he went into
the sanctuary of God, he understood the
end of the wicked. Now skip down to
verse 20. Let's read about that.
as a dream
>> when one awaketh.
>> So, oh Lord, when thou awakest, thou
shalt despise their image. So the Lord
is going to despise the image of those
that are wicked and prospering and
boastful and prideful.
But he did not understand that until he
went into the house of the Lord. Now
let's go to Hebrews 10. Hebrews 10.
and we going to read verses 23 to 25.
When you get it, go ahead, brother.
Let us hold fast a profession of our
faith without wavering, for he is
faithful that promise.
>> And let us consider one another to
provoke unto love and to good works. But
not forsaking the assemblies of
ourselves together, as the manner of
some is, but exhorting one another. and
so much the more as ye see the day
approaching.
>> So this is a benefit in coming to class
and studying the word of God and having
fellowship.
You know it says let us hold fast to our
faith without wavering and provoke one
another onto good works not forsaking
the assembling of ourselves as the
manner of some is. We can't do that. Now
let's go to one other place. Let's go to
Hebrews 12 and we gonna read verses 9 to
11. Go ahead.
>> Hebrews 12:es 9- 11.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Furthermore, we had we have had our
fathers of our flesh which corrected us
and we gave them reverence. Shall we not
much rather be in subject unto the
father of spirit and live? Mhm.
>> But they for a few days chasing us after
their own pleasure, but he for our
profit that we might be partakers of his
holiness.
>> Mhm.
>> Now chastising for the present seems to
be joyous, but grievious, but
nevertheless afterward he yielded the
peaceful fruit of righteousness unto
them which are exercised thereby.
>> That's right. So if you getting some
chastisement,
you know, praise the Lord. But turn
around and do the things that you need
to do. And don't be envious of the
wicked because the wicked got an end
that you don't want no parts of. That's
all I got on that question. If somebody
would like to add, I will move on to the
next one.
>> Yeah, I want to add u Jeremiah 12. Just
a few verses in Jeremiah 12 because he
asked that question too.
>> Okay.
>> And we'll pick it up in verse one. Just
read three verses. Yes, sir.
>> Righteous thou are, oh Lord, when I
plead with thee, and let me talk with
thee for thy judgment. Wherefore doth
the way of the wicked prosper? And
wherefore are all they happy that deal
very treacherously? But thou hast
planted them. Yeah, they have taken
root, and they grow. Yeah, they bring
forth fruit, and thou art near their
mouth, and far from their reign. Thou,
oh Lord, knowest me. Thou hast seen me,
and tried my heart towards thee. Pull
them out like sheep for the slaughter,
and prepare them for the day of
slaughter.
>> Yeah, that's the end of the wicked. But
the thing is, you know, what are we
doing? We got to we can't worry about
somebody else. We got to make sure that
we are doing what we need to do.
>> Absolutely.
>> So, that's all I got. We'll move on to
the next question. Sister Deborah,
>> moving on. Aalia Israel says, "So if
people missed the son's kingdom, they
were not resurrected with him nor alive
upon his arrival. They must be waiting
for the white throne judgment." However,
how can individuals make it to the
father's kingdom if they don't go
through the son's kingdom first? Is
there a pruning process in judgment as
there's a purging process during the sun
reign? Ezekiel 20 verse 38 is given and
the question again is how can
individuals make it to the father's
kingdom if they don't go through the
son's kingdom first.
>> So we're going to ask the guest caller
to address that question guest caller.
>> Yes. Well, the whole thing is there is
nothing written on that.
But uh uh uh so you know we don't uh uh
uh uh but we do know one thing that
you're going to have some that's going
to be saved. And the reason we know they
going to be saved is because God is
going to have a judgment at the white
throne judgment. God is not a vain God.
If you if they was not going if there
was no one to be saved after that
thousand years, then the Lord would not
have had a judgment. To give you a good
example, let's go into Revelation the
19th chapter and read verses 19 and 20.
And I saw the beasts and the kings of
the earth and their armies gathered
together to make war against him that
sat on the horse and against his army.
And the beast was taken, and with him
the false prophet that wrought miracles
before him, with which he deceived them
that had received the mark of the beast,
and them that worshiped his image. And
these both were cast alive into the lake
of fire burning with brimstone.
>> Now
if the Lord if if uh if the Lord was not
going to save some of them, he did just
like this. It wouldn't be no white
throne judgment. When it finally came,
they would have got thrown directly in
the lake of fire. Like these two guys,
they didn't stand in judgment.
They was alive when the Lord came. On
the way down, the Lord grabbed them and
that's when the create the lake of fire
was created and he threw them in it
directly.
But the people in the white throne
judgment by reason of the fact that they
are standing in judgment tells me that
some are going to be saved. Otherwise,
it wouldn't be no white throne judgment.
But what the Lord's going to do to vet
them, that's a question you have to ask
the Lord when you're sin. That's all I
have to say.
>> Thank you for that guest. Okay. Uh
Ezekiel 20 verse 38. Could that be read?
>> We can read it. Go ahead.
>> And I will purge out from among you the
rebels and them that transgress against
me. And I will bring them forth out of
the country where they sjourn, and they
shall not enter into the land of Israel,
and ye shall know that I am the Lord.
So the answer is still the same. After
thousand year millennium period, we
don't know what method the Lord is going
to do, but we know that some people are
going to be saved is because they are in
judgment. So whether uh uh uh uh so what
they did when and doing before after
Jesus came and brought everybody to the
wilderness and purge out the rebels, we
know that. But what's going to happen at
the thousand-y year millennium period?
We don't know that because it's not
written. So the answer is the same
because they're in judgment. Somebody
somebody in that judgment is going to be
saved. Otherwise they be just like the
beast and false prophet cast directly
into the lake of fire. That's all I have
to say.
>> Right.
All right. Sister Deborah, let us move
on to the next question.
>> Okay. Uh Aalia also says, "Shouldn't we
be taking our freedom or free time
seriously as to continue growing into a
wise and understanding people without
feeling like we're always in a
concentrated
environment as a text test puppy, but
with the gives and takes of the world to
study ready to show ourself approved and
rest in second Timothy 2 4-15
are given.
>> So we're going to ask brother Julius to
address that question. Brother Julius
you on mute.
>> Thank you Dre. The whole subject matter
of second Timothy uh 4-15 actually from
the beginning is about overcoming in
this flesh and blood body not just
Israel that is what man was created for
to overcome
uh uh sin to overcome yourself so that
you could be born into the very spirit
family of God. Let's read uh let's let's
read um let's go to second Timothy. We
going to go we not going to read the
whole chapter. just going to hit some
spots right here so we can answer this
right here because the whole duty of man
is to fear God and keep his
commandments. Has nothing to do with
being a test puppy. It is about uh what
we did against our God. He put us in
captivity so that uh we can learn how to
work out our salvation and be the
teachers to the whole world.
Uh second Timothy 2 start in verse three
and four. Go ahead uh Tenzel. Second
Timothy 2 3 and four. Go ahead.
>> Second Timothy 2 3 and 4.
>> Yep.
>> Second Timothy 2.
>> Okay.
>> 3 and 4.
>> So thou therefore endure hardness as a
good soldier of Jesus Christ.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And no man that warth entangled himself
with the affairs of this life, that he
may please him who have chosen him to be
a soldier. So that's what we are
supposed to be soldiers in the army of
the Lord and we are created uh uh that's
why Ephesians 6 tells you put on the
whole armor of God. You got to overcome
stuff. Give me verse 10.
>> Therefore I endure all things for the
elect's sake that they may also obtain
the salvation which is in Christ Jesus
with eternal glory.
>> Give me verse 14 to 15.
of these things. Put them in
remembrance, charging them before the
Lord, that they strive not about words
to no profit, but to the subverting of
the hearers.
>> Go ahead.
>> Study to show thyself approved unto God,
a workman that needeth not to be
ashamed, rightfully dividing the word of
truth.
>> Exactly. That's why you got to study to
show yourself approval unto God because
he's the one that's got the your life,
even your eternal life in his hands.
Last verse 21.
>> If a man therefore purge himself from
these, he shall be a vessel unto honor,
sanctified and meat for the master use,
and prepared unto every good work.
>> So that's what the whole chapter really
is all about. How to walk in this flesh
and blood life. has nothing about being
a test puppy or uh in a concentrated
anything, but it's about growing. Yes,
you're right about growing in grace and
growing uh to qualify yourself to become
a part of the very spirit family of God.
That's all I got on that.
>> Right. Grow in grace and grow in
knowledge, knowhow,
>> and keep the commandments. Uh you want
salvation, that's what this is all
about. Keep the commandments. Fight the
good fight of faith. That's all I got.
Dre.
>> Thank you, brother Julius. Sister
Deborah, next question.
>> Next question. Jennifer Love asks in
Joshua 5 13 and 14. Who is the captain
of the host of the Lord's army?
>> Let's go there quickly.
>> Right, Jew?
>> Joshua 5 and read it when you get there.
Joshua 5:13-14.
>> And it came to pass when Joshua was by
Jericho that he lifted up his eyes and
looked, and behold, there stood a man
over him with the sword drawn in his
hand.
>> And Joshua went unto him, and said unto
him, Art thou for us, or for our
adversaries?
And he said, Nay, but as captain of the
host of the Lord, am I now come? And
Joshua fell on his face to the earth and
did worship and said unto him, "What
sayeth my lord unto his servant?"
>> Now let's go. Let's get to who this
captain is. Let's go to Daniel 12.
Daniel 12:1. This is none other than
Michael the archangel. He is the captain
uh or the chief prince over the lowest
angels over his army.
Daniel 12 and verse one.
When you get it, go ahead, brother.
>> And at that time shall Michael stand up,
the great prince, which standeth for the
children of thy people. And there shall
be a time of trouble such as never was
said there was a nation, even to that
same time. And at that time thy people
shall be delivered, everyone that shall
be found written in the book. Now that's
this is Michael the captain of the
Lord's host. One last place Daniel 12
Daniel 12 and verse 7.
>> And I heard the man
>> Revelation 12. Revelation 12 and 7.
Notice what it says. Michael Michael.
Revelation 12 and verse 7. And we'll be
done.
When you get it to you, go ahead and
read it. And there was war in heaven.
Michael and his angels fought against
the dragon. And the dragon fought and
his angels.
>> So now this is none other than Michael.
That's why it says Michael and his
angels because Michael is the captain of
the Lord's host. The archangel Michael
is the answer. I hope that helped.
>> Thank you, brother Julius. Sister
Deborah, time check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:05.
Jolity
says according to Exodus 20:10,
no one within thy gates can work. Is
that to say no one on your property?
What about a rental property?
>> We're going to ask Brother Jerome to
answer that question. Brother Jerome,
>> yeah, it it includes all that and and
and more actually, you know. Um, nobody
is supposed to be doing any work. Your
man servant, your maid servant,
common terms, those that work for you,
they ain't supposed to be working
either. Okay? No matter where they are,
it don't matter if it's in your house on
your job or rental property. Don't
matter. They not supposed to be working.
But let's go read the verse.
Uh, Exodus 20:10,
>> but the seventh day is a Sabbath of the
Lord thy God. In it, thou shall not do
any work, thou, nor that son, nor that
daughter, that man's servant, nor that
maid servant, nor that cattle, nor that
stranger that is within thy gates.
>> Yeah. So, it don't matter if they they
working for you, they not supposed to be
work. You're not supposed to be working.
And neither of the people that's working
for you supposed to be working,
>> right?
>> Okay. There's one law for all. What the
Bible say
>> for the stranger as well as for for
Israel.
>> Yeah.
>> I won't interject.
>> I want to interject something.
When it come to rental property, if you
rent it, then it just like it's theirs.
>> Okay. Now, if you don't want to rent a
person something because they going to
open on the Sabbath day, then you do not
rent it. But once you rent it, then they
are paying you.
>> Yeah.
>> Then you are responsible for what they
do, not you.
>> Thank you for that.
>> Yes, sir.
We going to move on. Sister Deborah,
next question.
>> Next question. Valencia asked for you to
explain Romans 4:es
4 and five.
>> Okay, let's go to that Romans 4 and we
going to start at verse three. We going
to read a little bit in Romans here.
Romans 4 and read verses 3 to 5. Go
ahead, brother.
>> For what said the scripture? Abraham
believed God, and it was counted unto
him for righteousness.
But now to him that workketh is the
reward not reckon of grace, but of
death. But to him that workketh not, but
believed on him that justifith the
ungodly, his faith is counted for
righteousness.
>> Yeah. Exactly. So we we are going to uh
deal with this a little bit because it
says here
Abraham believed God and it was counted
to him for righteousness.
So it started with Abraham's belief but
his belief was manifested in his
actions.
Now skip down to verse 16, brother. Go
ahead.
Therefore, it is of faith that it might
be by grace till the end of the promise
might be sure to all the seed, but not
to that only which is of the law, but to
that also which is of the faith of
Abraham, who is the father of us all.
Now the faith of Abraham is that the
promise that was given to Abraham is
that in Abraham's seed shall all nations
of the earth be blessed. That seed being
Christ.
Abraham being the father of many nations
and they coming up under that covenant
that was given to Abraham. Read verse 17
brother.
As it is written, I have made thee a
father of many nations before him whom
he believed, even God, who quickened the
dead, and calleth those things which be
not as though they were.
>> Now it says, as it is written, I have
made thee the father of many nations,
before whom he believed. Abraham
believed when he said, I have made thee
the father of many nations. Even though
Abraham did not have a son at that time,
he said, "Even God, who quickenth the
dead and calleth those things that be
not as though they were."
Now, that's verse 17. Skip down to verse
20. Go ahead.
>> He staggered not at the promise of God
through unbelief, but was strong in
faith, giving glory to God.
>> So Abraham's faith was strong. He did
not stagger when God made that promise
to him. Even though it didn't come, his
child didn't come until like 25 years
later.
Read that verse one more time, brother.
>> He staggered not at the promise of God
through unbelief, but was strong in
faith, giving glory to God.
>> Go ahead. and being fully persuaded that
what he had promised he was able also to
perform.
>> So whatever God promised Abraham,
Abraham believed it and he believed that
God was able to perform it. Verse 22, go
ahead.
>> And therefore it was imputed to him for
righteousness. And Abraham's
righteousness
was the work that he did in following
everything that God told him to do.
Abraham didn't just believe with lip
service. Abraham believed with actions.
>> That's right.
>> Now, let's let's go to James 1 and we
going to read verse 22.
James 1 and 22.
Go ahead when you get it, brother.
>> But be ye doers of the word and not
hearers only, deceiving your own selves.
>> Yeah. Because if if you just a believer
and you not a doer, you are deceiving
your own self. Go right over to 20 uh to
the second chapter now. And I want you
to pick it up at verse 21. Read to 23.
Go ahead.
Was not Abraham our father justified by
works when he had offered Isaac his son
upon the altar?
But seeest thou how faith wrought with
his works and by works with faith made
perfect.
>> And the scripture was fulfilled which
said Abraham believed God and it was
imputed unto him for righteousness and
he was called the friend of God. Notice
that verse 23, he said, "And the
scripture was fulfilled which
saith,"Abraham
believed God, and it was imputed onto
him for righteousness, and he was called
a friend of God because Abraham's
actions bagged up his belief." And we
read last week, we gonna read this one
last time. Let's go to Genesis 26 and we
just gonna read five and that's it.
Genesis 26 and5. Go ahead when you get
it, brother.
>> Because that Abraham obeyed my voice and
kept my charge, my commandments, my
statutes, and my laws.
>> Yeah. Like James said, faith without
works is dead. And Abraham's faith was
bagged up with works. and by by his
works was his faith made perfect. That's
all I got on that.
Sister Deborah, we'll move on to the
next question.
>> Moving on. RCJR
asks, "Does BL mean Lord in Hosea 2
verse 16? Then if so, why do we call him
Lord? And what can we call him if this
is the case? I think this is future
prophecy, but I want to clarify.
>> We're going to ask the guest caller to
clarify this. Guest caller.
>> Okay,
let's go and read Hosea 2 and 16.
Was that Hosea 2 and 15?
>> Two and 16.
And it shall be at that day, sayeth the
Lord, that thou shalt call me Ishi, and
shall call me no more bail.
>> Now, we're going to examine that. Does
that say that that uh uh Lord means
bail?
>> No. No.
>> Ain't nowhere to Lord mean bail.
He said that you at that day you going
to call me Ishi
>> and no more bail that why that's once
you are under the covenant and he have
married you that's why it's talking
about the wedding the marriage of the
lamb so ishi that mean my husband let's
go quickly and show you that uh uh uh uh
let's ask once the lord marry you let's
go quickly
to uh Jeremiah 3 and read verse 14.
>> Jeremiah 3
and 14.
>> 14.
>> So turn, oh backsliding children, sayeth
the Lord, for I am married unto you, and
I will take you one of a city, two of a
family, and I will bring you to Zion.
So he said, turn cuz I'm married to you.
That mean that he is he is uh uh uh he
is going to be the husband of Israel.
That's what uh and when people get
baptized, you marry in the Lord. Let's
go quickly to Isaiah.
>> Isaiah
the uh 54th chapter and read verse five
and six.
For thy maker is thy husband, the Lord
of hosts is his name, and thy redeemer,
the holy one of Israel, the God of the
whole earth, shall he be called.
>> Okay? So
your husband is your maker. That's why
it's talking about the marriage of the
lamb. When he bring Israel in, then
that's when the marriage start there in
the wilderness. That's why he say going
to bring you into the bond of the
covenant in Ezekiel the 20th chapter.
>> But as far as Lord
men being Baal, that is not written in
the Bible. I've heard this uninformed
statement
too many time about Baal and Lord being
the same. If that's the case, then the
Lord himself don't know who he is. Go to
Exodus the 20th chapter and start
reading that verse one. So you telling
me that God called himself Baal? That's
kind of strange to me. Exodus 20 and
one. Read it when you start when you get
there.
>> And God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God which hath brought
thee out of the land of E.
>> Wait a minute. Wait a minute. Wait a
minute. And God spoke all these words,
saying what? I am what?
>> The Lord thy God.
>> Oh. Oh. If if Lord mean Ba, then he
saying I am Baal thy God. Ain't this
what it mean?
>> Mhm.
>> If that was correct and it ain't
correct,
>> right? If Lord Baal,
he so it would read, I am the I am the I
am the Baal thy God. But he said, "The
Lord thy God," keep reading,
>> "which have brought thee out of the land
of Egypt, out of the house of God,
>> thou have no other gods before me."
>> Now, this is what he's talking about.
All them other gods, they come under
them pagan gods come under the laws of
Baal. So he said, "When I bring you back
and I bring into the B of the covenant,
which is I'm going to marry you, then
you're going to call me my husband, and
you ain't going to be dealing with all
them pagan gods that come out of the
hidden veil, like the god of sun and the
god of Easter,
>> right?
>> So the Lord Lord do not mean bail. That
is a falsehood that's been out a long
time and you cannot read it in the
Bible. That is right.
>> The reason and the reason you going to
call him Ishi cuz Ish ish mean my
husband is because you going to be
married to him.
>> Right.
>> That's all.
>> That is right. Thank you for that guest
caller. Sister Deborah. Next question
please.
>> Next question. Sophia Ball says, "Can
you explain Matthew 24
and 41 and Luke 17 34 and 35?
Where is the one being taken to and what
will happen to the other?"
>> We're going to ask uh Brother Jerome to
explain that question. Brother Jerome,
>> let's go read the verses given in the
question. Um, Matthews 24 verse 40 and
41.
Go ahead and read.
>> Then shall two be in the field. The one
shall be taken and the other left. Two
women shall be grinding at the meal. The
one shall be taken and the other left.
>> Okay. In Luke 17
verse 34 and35
I tell you in that night there shall be
two men in one bed and one shall be
taken and the other shall be left and
two women shall be grinding together.
The one shall be taken and the other
left.
>> Okay.
So where is the one that's being taken?
Okay. Let's give you an example first
and then we'll tie this to the first
resurrection. Okay? But let's go to Acts
chapter 1.
Let's give an example of this taken.
Okay.
Acts chapter 1 and read verse 11.
Go ahead and read.
which also said, "Ye men of Galilee, why
stand ye gazing up into heaven? This
same Jesus which is taken up from you
into heaven shall so come in like manner
as you have seen him go into heaven."
>> So in the first resurrection, those
that's taken, they going to be taken up
to the second heaven. They going to meet
the Lord in the in the air and in the
clouds, right?
>> That's where they going to be taken.
Okay? Now, the ones that's left,
let's go give you some examples of that.
Cuz if they didn't make the first
resurrection and the Lord didn't kill
them and they still alive, they still
flesh and blood, what they going to be
doing? Let's go to um Zechariah 14,
read verse 1 and three, and then we
going to skip.
>> Zechariah 14.
>> Yeah.
Read verse uh
1 and 1 through 3 and then skip to verse
16.
Go ahead.
>> Behold, the day of the Lord cometh, and
thy spoil shall be divided in the midst
of thee. I will gather all nations
against Jerusalem to battle, and the
city shall be taken, and the house is
rifled, and the women ravaged, and half
of the city shall go forth into
captivity, and the residue of the people
shall not be cut off of the city. Mhm.
>> Then shall the Lord go forth and fight
against those nations. That's when he
fought in the day of battle.
>> Strip down to verse five. Cuz now the
ones that's taken to meet the Lord in
there, these are the ones in this fifth
verse. Read it.
>> And ye shall flee to the valley of the
mountains. For the valley of the
mountains shall reach unto Ael. Yeah. He
shall flee like as he fled from before
the earth from before the earthquake in
the days of Uzziah, king of Judah. The
Lord my God shall come and all the
saints with thee.
>> Yeah. They made them in the air and in
the clouds. That's where they was taken.
All right. All right. So now skip down
to verse 16. This is an example of those
others that didn't make the first
resurrection, but they weren't killed.
All right. Go ahead. And it shall come
to pass that everyone that is left of
all the nations which came against
Jerusalem because all them nations going
to be sending their armies, right? The
Lord going to slay every one of them in
every one of them armies. But them
nations going to still be on this planet
alive that he didn't kill. And what they
going to have to do? Read.
>> Which came against Jerom shall even go
up from year to year to worship the
King, the Lord of hosts, and to keep the
feasts of tabernacles.
>> Yeah, I can give you more, but that I
think that should be enough. That's all
I got.
>> Yes, sir.
All right. We hope that that answered
your question for you, Sister Deborah.
We'll move on to the next one. Moving
on. Be alert wants you to explain
Matthew 6
17 and 18. Jesus said anointing your
head before you fast. Is it still
optional to anoint your head?
>> We going to go to that Matthew 6:17 and
18 and we'll ask the guest caller to
explain that scripture. Guest caller. Go
>> read. Go read it first.
But thou
>> go ahead.
>> But thou, when thou fastest, anoint thy
head, and wash thy face, that thou
appear not unto men to fast, but unto
thy father which is in secret, and thy
father which seeth in secret shall
reward thee openly.
>> Now, this don't have nothing to do with
a ritual.
All they said is when you fast, do like
you always do. Get up in the morning.
Now nowadays, you get up in the morning
and we got this kinky hair. We put
grease in that hair or oil.
>> We wash our face. We brush our teeth,
>> right?
>> And go on about our business. Instead of
walking around looking like we uh uh uh
got a problem and we suffering. But if
you had backed up and read the verse
before that, verse 16, it'll tell you
what it explains what you mean. You just
read read one verse uh uh before 17.
Read it.
>> Oh, when ye fast, be not as the
hypocrites of a sad continent. For they
defiges
that they might appear unto men to fast.
But verily I say unto you, they have
their reward.
So you see what it says here.
>> Mhm.
>> Just get up and fix up like you do every
day when you get ready to leave your
house
instead of getting up and leave home.
You're all done. Why you looking all
sick? You know what's wrong with you?
I'm fasting.
Then you done got your reward,
>> right?
>> Got nothing to do with no anointing the
head and going through no kind of
ritual. is all simply saying if you
fasting don't let nobody know it. Get up
and do everything you do every day.
>> Right.
>> Okay. That's all I have to say.
>> Thank you. Guest caller.
>> Sister Deborah. Next question.
>> Next question. Marcia Samuels asks,
"If a man divorce,
uh, if a man divorced
due to his wife being unfaithful,
if he remarried,
is he committing adultery? Also, his new
wife, is she in sin?"
>> No.
Let's go to Matthew the 19th chapter.
Matthew 19. And let's pick it up at
verse three. We're going to read 3-6.
Go ahead when you get it, Tanzania.
>> Pharisees also came unto him, tempting
him, and saying unto him, It is lawful
for a man to put away his wife for every
cause. And he answered and said unto
them, "Have you not read that he which
made them at the beginning made them
male and female?
And said, for this cause should a man
leave father and mother, and shall
cleave to his wife, and they twain shall
be one flesh.
Wherefore they are no more twain, but
one flesh. What therefore God have
joined together, let not man put us
under."
>> That's right. what the Lord joined
together. Don't let man put us under.
Now read verse nine. Skip down to nine
and read that.
Now I say unto you, whosoever shall put
away his wife, except it be for
fornication, and shall marry another
committeth adultery. And whosoever
marrith her which is put away, do commit
adultery. So you see here that is the
only exception
in that case and that is fornication. So
no you you're not uh sinning if you
marry and this person that was married
before his mate or her mate committed
adultery.
That's all I got on that.
Sister Deborah, next question.
Next question. Timeout Houston asks, "To
be saved from eternal torment, do we
need to believe in Jesus, be
circumcised, get baptized, and keep the
10 plus commandments?"
>> Brother Julius, do we need to do all
these things that I mentioned here?
>> You know what? Uh, all those answers
were yes, except uh when he got when he
said the 10 plus commandments.
when he said attempt to be saved from
the lake of fire which is eternal to
eternal torment. Do we need to believe
in Jesus? Yes. Do you need to be
circumcised if you're a male? Yes. You
need to get baptized in Jesus' name?
Yes. And keep the 10 commandments.
You got commandments that's that are
that are encompassed in the
commandments. But the Lord gave you ten
commandments and book and the book tell
you he added no more. So the answer is
we going to stay right here in Matthew
the 19th chapter uh tenzel and let's
look at what Jesus said
Matthew 19
and pick it up at verse 16.
And behold one came and said unto him
good master what good thing shall I do
that I may have eternal life?
>> Yes.
>> And he said unto him why callst thou me
good? There is none good but one that is
God.
>> Uhuh.
>> We'll enter into life. Keep the
commandments.
>> Keep the commandments. And that is the
ten commandments sisters and brothers.
And then the rest of he gave you just a
few of them. The name to remind you that
it is the ten commandments. But the
bottom line is is your question is yes.
But when you say the 10 plus
commandments, you know, all the dietary
law, all the feast days, all those are
encompassed within the ten commandments.
>> But it's the book told you he gave you
10 and he added no more.
>> And you can read that in Deuteronomy the
4th chapter on your own. We open up with
Exodus the 20th chapter 1-17, the ten
commandments. So let's drop the plus and
the answer to everything else is yes. I
hope that helped. Thank you, brother
Julia. Sister Deborah, moving right
along.
>> Moving right along. The key wild goose
wants explanation on 2 Corinians
5:8.
>> We're going to ask brother Jerome to
address that question. Brother Jerome,
let's go read the verse.
That's
>> 2 Corinthians 5 and8.
>> Yeah.
We are confident, I say, and willing
rather to be absent from the body and to
be present with the Lord.
>> Okay? Um, you you can't leave out words
when you're dealing with verses in the
Bible because when you do that, you
going to get a different uh explanation
as to what that verse is saying. There's
one word you're ignoring in that verse,
okay? And that word is rather. He would
rather be absent. He didn't say he is
absent.
He say he would rather. Okay? I would
rather be a millionaire.
That don't mean I'm a millionaire. Okay?
All right. And so read verse uh let's
let's go um to let's go to first
Thessalonians chapter 2 cuz Apostle Paul
that made this statement he know when
he's going to be present with the Lord.
Okay. So I'm going to let him tell you.
All right. First Thessalonians chapter 2
verse 19.
Go ahead.
For what is our hope or joy or crown of
rejoicing?
Are not even ye in the presence of our
Lord Jesus Christ at his coming? And the
answer is yes.
At his coming. That's when you present
with the Lord. So he said, I would
rather be present with the Lord, but I
know I have to wait
>> right
>> until he come. All right. And I'm gonna
meet him in air and in the clouds.
That's what it tell you in
Thessalonians. All right. So, now let's
go to 1 Corinthians chapter 15.
And we're going to pick it up at verse
21. Read it to the 23.
For since by man came death, by man came
also the resurrection of the dead.
For as in Adam all died, and even so in
Christ shall all be made alive.
But every man in his own order, Christ
the first fruits afterward they that are
Christ at his coming.
>> Telling you at his coming. And that's
when we going to be present with the
Lord if we be so blessed to make that
first resurrection.
That's all I got on.
>> Thank you, brother Jerome. Great answer,
Sister Deborah. Next question.
>> Next question. Uh, Timeout Houston says,
"What about people who keep some but not
all? Like those in the Middle East who
keeps commandments but are are not
baptized or people in the West who
believe in Jesus and are baptized but
not circumcised."
We're
>> going to ask the guest caller to answer
that question. Guest caller.
Okay, let's go.
First thing we going to deal with the
baptism part, right?
Let's go into Mark 16 and 16.
>> Mark 16.
He that believeth
He that believeth and is baptized shall
be saved. He that believeth not shall be
damned.
>> So now if you if you don't get baptized
then you don't believe.
So but if you believe and get baptized
you're going to be saved. But if you
don't believe you're going to be damned.
This is the reason why. Go to Galatians
the 3 chapter and read verse 26- 29.
For ye are all the children of God by
faith in Christ Jesus.
For as many of you as have been baptized
into Christ have put on Christ. There is
neither Jew nor Greek. There is neither
bond nor free. There is neither male nor
female. For ye are all one in Christ
Jesus. And if ye be Christ, then are ye
Abraham's seed and hes according to the
prophecy.
>> So now in order for you become Abraham's
seed, because the Lord said in thy seed,
talking to Abraham, shall all the
nations of the earth be blessed. Now, if
you want to get the uh uh uh uh uh
receive the promise as Abraham seed, you
got to be baptized because and baptized
in the name of Jesus. So, that's going
to put you under the blood of the
covenant. And you going to tell me you
believe and don't get baptized, then
like the book say, you going to be
damned. Now, as far as the circumcision
is concerned,
and if you get baptized and you're not
circumcised, you going to get cut off.
Let's go into Genesis the 17th chapter
and read verse 14.
Read it when you get there.
Genesis 17 and verse 14.
And the uncircumcised manchild whose
flesh of his foreskin is not
circumcised, that soul should be cut off
from his people. He have broken my
covenant.
>> That don't need any explanation, does
it?
>> Oh, so
>> that's why if you ain't circumcised, why
get baptized? You cut going to get cut
off anyway cuz you broken the covenant
that God made with Abraham.
He say any man child whether he's Israel
or a stranger
do not if you don't get baptized you
don't believe if you don't and if
because uh no matter what you try to do
so now in both cases you going to get
cut off that's all I have to say.
>> Yes sir.
>> All right uh sister Deborah let us move
on to the next question.
>> Moving on. um read the Bible daily asks,
"Are there any scriptures that directly
show time correlates to one year and
times correlate to two years?"
>> We're going to ask Brother Julius to
answer that question. Brother Julius?
>> Yes. Uh absolutely. Uh you might want to
get a pen and paper and write this down
because we going to do a little math
real quick. There are 30 days biblically
speaking in a biblical year. There are
30 days in a month. There are 360 days
in a year. So one year is 12 months.
It's like your car note is like your car
note. You have an agreement with how
many years. 3 years are 36 months. One
year is 12 months. Two years is 24
months. 3 years is 36 month. And a half
a year is 6 months. That equals for one
year. Let's go. Let's go to the Bible.
Let's go to Revelation 11 and2.
Revelation 11 and2.
We're going to use uh the great
tribulation period of 3 and 1/2 years
formula.
Revelation 11. And when you get it,
Tazil read verse two.
>> But the court which is without the
temple, leave out and measure it not.
For it is given unto the Gentiles and
the holy city shall they tread underfoot
40 and two months.
>> 42 months is three and a half years.
3 and 1/2 years. Now Revelation 12 and
6.
Revelation 12. Remember 42 months. 3 and
1/2 years.
Revelation 12 and six. Tanzania. Go
ahead. And the woman fled into the
wilderness where she had had a place
prepared of God that they should feed
her there a,23
score days.
>> That is 1,260
days which is three and a half years.
Let's go to Daniel
7.
Daniel the 7th chapter and we talking
about the same time Daniel prophesied
about it. Daniel 7 and read verse 25.
>> And he shall speak great words against
the most high and shall wear out the
saints of the most high and think to
change times and laws and they shall be
given unto his hand unto a time and
times and the dividing of time.
>> So now a time is one year, times is two
years and and a half a time is six
months. All of that is the same thing.
three and one half years.
>> Right?
>> That's all I got. I hope that helped.
>> Thank you, brother Julius. We hope that
that helps. We will move on, Sister
Deborah, to our next question.
>> Yes. Sander Herring wants you to explain
2 Corinthians 3 6 and 7.
>> Let's go to that. 2 Corinthians 3 6 and
7. And we'll ask the guest caller to
address that question.
Guest caller.
>> Second Corinthians 3 verse 6 and 7. Who
also have made us able ministers of the
New Testament, but not of the letter,
but of the spirit. For the letter kleth,
the spirit giveth life. But if the
ministration of death written and
engraved in stones was glorious, so that
the children of Israel could not
steadfastly behold the face of Moses for
the glory of his countenance which glory
was to be done away.
>> Okay, first thing is let's look at the
administration of death. Man was not
created to die,
but he blew up the mission. First, let's
go into uh Psalms 82. We're going to
read verse 1 and two and skip down and
read verse 6 and 7.
Read it when you get there.
I have said ye are God and all of you
are the children of the most high but ye
should die like men and fall like one of
the princes.
>> You see and uh uh uh did you read one
and two first?
>> Oh I'm sorry. God standeth in the
congregation of the mighty. He judgeth
among the gods. How long will ye judge
unjustly and accept the person of the
wicked?
>> Now he say standeth in the congregation
of the mighty and he judges among the
gods. He was he's talking about man
here. God ain't supposed to die. But we
accepted the person of the wicked. So
what happened? Now you skip down and
read
>> verse six. I have said ye are gods and
all of you
>> I have said you are gods. Go ahead.
>> And all of you are children of the most
high.
>> Huh?
>> Ye shall die like men and fall like one
of the princes.
>> So now ever since God uh that Adam and
Eve messed up, God brought in death.
From that day on, we have been under the
administration of death, no matter what
we did. But let's look, let's go a
little further. Let's go into uh 1
Corinthians the 15th chapter and let's
look how it happened.
1 Corinthians 15 and we're going to
start reading at verse 21. 15 and 21.
Okay, read it.
For since by man came death, by man came
also the resurrection of the dead.
For as in Adam all died, but even so in
Christ shall all be made alive.
But every man in his own.
>> Go ahead, finish it.
>> But every man in his own order, Christ
the first fruits, afterwards they that
are Christ at his coming.
So now
man is the one that brought death. In
fact through Adam man died. So when
Jesus come through him we all going to
be made alive.
And once we are made alive uh uh uh uh
and and once and and and that life is
talking about eternal life. But until
until that time we are under
administration of death. even if you
keep the commandments. And Jesus not
died for us, we be in trouble. But then
it said they was not able to look up on
Moses because Moses because his face
started to shine. What happened to
Moses? He started to take on him the
characteristics of an immortal.
Let's go into Daniel the 12th chapter
and read verses 2 and three to show you
why they couldn't look up on Moses. He
had to put a veil over his face because
he became a being of light. That's what
the God is. 12 and three. Read it when
you get there.
>> And many of them that slept in the dust
of the earth shall awake, some to
everlast everlasting life, and some to
shame and everlasting contempt.
>> And they that be wise shall shine as the
brightness of the firmament. and they
that turn many to righteousness as the
stars forever and ever.
>> Now when Moses come down
uh uh from with them commandments from
being up there in 40 days and 40 nights
close to the Lord, he started to take on
the characteristics of a of an immortal
spirit being. He started to shine. They
couldn't look up on it. But still they
was under administration of death
because it had not been removed. So if
you kept the commandments,
still you was under the administration
of death
and you could not get out from under it
until the Lord came and died for your
sin. That's the only way you could be
saved. Let's go into Hebrews the 2
chapter. Read verse 9 first. Then we're
going to skip down to 14 and 15. Hebrews
2 and 9.
But we see Jesus who was made a little
lower than the angels for the suffering
of death crown with the glory and honor
that he by the grace of God should taste
death for every man.
>> Now he had to come and take and die for
every man. Skip down and read verse 14
and 15. Go ahead. For as much then, as
the children are partakers of flesh and
blood, he also himself likewise took
part of the saint, that through death he
might destroy him that had the power of
death, and that is the devil.
And delivered them who through fear of
death were all their lifetime subject to
bondage.
So, so the whole thing is until Jesus
came and died, we was under
administration of death. There was no
other way to get out of it until Jesus
came and died. And when he died, let's
see what happened to death. 1
Corinthians 15, read verses 24- 26.
Then cometh the end when he shall have
delivered up the kingdom to God, even
the father, when he shall have put down
all rule and all authority and power.
26 26
>> The last enemy that shall be destroyed
is death.
>> Now when Jesus come and terminate death,
you can't die no more. We will no longer
be under the administration of death
because nobody will be dying anymore.
>> Right?
>> So all Paul is saying is that look it is
glorious walking the commandment but
still you are under administration of
death. And until Jesus came and died for
your sins and terminated death you will
be under administration of death. But
once he terminated death we are no
longer under the administration of
death. That's all I got to say.
That is right. The wages of sin is death
and the gift of God is eternal life in
Jesus Christ.
>> Yes sir.
>> Sister,
>> let's move on to the next question.
Sister De,
>> next question. And he also asks in
Exodus 20 4 and 5, it mentioned not
bowing down to graven images or anything
in heaven, earth or the waters. Please
explain Genesis 43
verse 26 and 28.
>> We're going to ask brother Julius to
explain that. Brother Julius,
>> let's do this right here. Let instead of
starting at verse four, let's start at
uh Exodus 20 and verse three.
Now, so we can identify that who the
them is that we not supposed to bow down
to or worship. Exodus 20 and three.
Tanzel, when you get it, go ahead.
>> Thou shalt have no other gods before me.
>> Continue.
Thou shalt not make thee any graven
image or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above or that the earth
beneath or that is in the water under
the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thyself to them
nor serve them. Why the Lord thy God am
a jealous God visiting the iniquities of
the fathers upon the children unto the
third and fourth generation of them that
hate me.
>> That's good. Thank you, brother. So now
this is talking about you don't bow down
to no other pagan gods. You don't bow
down to nothing in the creation and
worship it as if it is God.
>> Right?
>> Now let's get to uh Genesis 43.
Remember we're talking gods, pagan gods.
Genesis 43 and read let's read that
scripture verse 26
and 28. Go ahead.
>> Genesis 43. Genesis 43:26 and verse 28.
Well, 26 through 28. Go ahead.
>> And when Joseph came home, they brought
him the present which was in their hand
into the house and bowed themselves to
him to the earth. And he asked him of
their welfare and said, "Is your father
well? The old man of whom ye spake, is
he yet alive?" And they answered, "Thy
servant our father is in good health. He
is yet alive." They bowed down their
heads and made obedience.
>> Now, this is Joseph. This whole story is
about Joseph, a flesh and blood man, no
gods, and their brothers and a prophecy
that needed to be fulfilled. So, when
they bowed down their head, they didn't
even know that uh Joseph was second in
command. He was viceroy of of Egypt.
Pharaoh had made him second in command.
And this was to fulfill the scripture.
They didn't know him. They thought he
was uh one of Pharaoh's officers and
they it's just like you see uh in
certain countries and even in Asian and
Arab communities they bow to each other
but it's a term of respect not to be
worshiped. Let's go to Genesis the 37th
chapter and let's look at this being
fulfilled. Genesis 37 we going to start
it out at verse 5. That's why he asked
him of is your father well? Genesis 37
and pick it up my brother Tazelle at
verse five. When you get it, go ahead
and read it.
>> And Joseph dreamed the dream. And he
told it his brother, and they hated him
yet the more.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And he said unto them, "Here, I pray you
this dream which I have dreamed."
>> So now he's telling them about the
dream. He's telling them about uh about
the dream. Skip down to verse seven. 7
to 10 quickly. Go ahead. For behold, we
are binding sheep in the field, and lo,
my sheep arose. And I also
>> Skip down to verse N. Skip down to verse
N.
>> And he dreamed yet another dream, and
told his brethren, and said, Behold, I
have dreamed a dream more, and behold,
the sun and the moon and the 11 star
made obesience to me.
And he told
>> the sun and the and and the moon and the
stars made obesience to me. Go ahead and
read. And he told it to his father and
to his brother. And his father rebuked
him and said unto him, But what is this
dream that thou has dreamed? Shall I and
thy mother and thy brethren indeed come
to bow thou myself to thee to the earth?
>> And they stood before their brothers in
in Genesis chapter 43. They stood before
their brother Joseph and bow down to
fulfill this prophecy.
>> Right? shall I, Jacob, your mother, the
the son, the moon, the wife, and the 11
stars in Revelation. And it'll tell you
that in another scripture in Revelation,
the 12th chapter, it tell you that uh
the sun, stars, and moon represented
Jacob, his wife, and the 11 sons. That's
why they bowed down to him because to
feel fulfill scripture, to fulfill this
dream. So that's what that's all about.
Not. They didn't worship Joseph. They
bowed down because he was viceroy or
second in command of Egypt and they paid
him total respect. I hope that helped.
Thank you, brother Julius, for that good
edification, Sister Deborah. Time check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:55.
We are now into tonight's Q&A for
Wednesday, September the 10th, 2025.
Baya Ben says,
"If it is true that Gabriel is the
comforter, the spirit of truth and the
Holy Ghost being the angel of the Lord.
Then is it Gabriel who moved across who
moved upon the face of the deep in
Genesis one? If not, then who was that?
>> Genesis.
>> So they wanted Yes. They want to know
was it Gabriel who moved upon the face
of the deep in Genesis one?
Well, let's go to that Genesis 1 and we
read one to uh two one and two and open
it to the panel.
Go ahead, brother Tanzia.
In the beginning, God created the
heavens and the earth.
And the earth was without form and void.
The darkness was upon the face of the
deep and the spirit of God moved upon
the face of the waters.
open.
>> Yes, God. The
>> spirit of God, too. That was an angel,
but uh uh uh
it wasn't Gabriel. It could be any other
angel. Gabriel is a messenger. Let's go
and let's go into Hebrews the first
chapter
and uh uh uh
and we're going to start at uh uh uh
six. We're going to read six and seven.
We going to skip down
>> 1 6 and 7. And we going to skip
>> Yeah, we going to skip down till the uh
uh
until the uh uh verse 14.
Read it.
And again, when he bringeth in the first
begotten into the world, he said, "Let
all the angels of God worship him, and
of the angels, he said, who make of his
angels spirits and his ministers a flame
of fire."
>> So now, his angels are spirits. Skip
down and read uh verse 14. These same
angels, go ahead. Are they not all
ministering spirits sent forth to
minister for them who shall be heirs of
salvation?
>> So now uh uh all these angels are
serving spirits. All of them are
spirits. They all do a whole lot of
stuff. But the one that's called that
bring the messages of God is the one
that's called Gabriel.
And uh uh uh let's see if we can do
something right quick with some
scripture where it say uh uh
where he sent his angel before them.
This is Gabriel
>> and uh uh
>> Isaiah 63.
>> Huh?
>> Is that Isaiah 63 you want?
>> No. I want to go to Exodus to show where
he say he sent his Exodus 23.
>> Exodus 23.
Yeah.
>> Right. Okay. Find that and read it. Then
we going to go and show you how they
rebel.
>> Exodus 23 and 20.
Behold, I send an angel before thee to
keep thee in the way, and to bring thee
into the place which I have prepared.
But beware of him, and obey his voice,
and provoke him not. For he will not
pardon your transgressions. For my name
is in him.
Now see, so this is the angel. This this
is talking about the one that brings the
message. Now let's go in Isaiah 63 and
show you what they rebel against it.
Let's see
and uh
start at verse 7. We're going to have to
read down to we're going to do a little
reading right quick.
Isaiah 63 and7. Yep.
>> I will mention the loving kindness of
the Lord and the praises of the Lord
according to all that the Lord hath
bestowed on us and the great goodness
towards the house of Israel which he
hath bestowed on them according to his
mercies and according to the multitude
of his loving kindness.
For he said, "Surely they are my people,
children that will not lie." So he was
their savior and in all their affliction
he was afflicted and the angels of his
presence saved them
in his love and in his pity he redeemed
them and he ba them and carried them all
the days of old.
>> So this is the angel of his presence.
He's the one that laid them and taught
them all days of old. But what did they
do? Go ahead.
>> So they rebelled and vex his holy
spirit. Therefore, he was turned to be
their enemy and he fought against them.
>> So, that's Gabriel. He is a Holy Spirit.
He's an angel and he and God make all
his angel spirits. So, he's holy. So, he
said he is the uh uh uh he said he's the
uh uh uh uh angel of the Lord's
presence.
>> That's right.
>> Let's go and see what he told uh
Zachchariah John the Baptist. Uh uh
daddy,
>> there's Luke.
>> Thank you.
>> Luke 1,
>> Luke the first chapter and pick it up at
uh verse 17 to 19.
>> Yeah. Okay.
and and he shall go before him in the
spirit and power of Isaiah to turn the
hearts of the father to the children and
the disobedient to the wisdom of the
just and to make ready a people prepared
for the Lord. And Zachchariah said unto
the angel, whereby shall I know this?
For I am a old man, and my wife
wellstricken in years. The angel
answered him, saying unto him, I am
Gabriel, that stand in the presence of
God,
and am sent to speak unto thee, and to
show thee these glad tidings.
>> So now, that's the same angel of God's
presence that the Lord sent before
Israel, the teacher. That's the same
Gabriel
uh uh uh uh that the Lord sent to
Daniel. You go read. That's the same
Gable that the Lord sent to John to tell
Mary that she is going to have a child.
So now Gable is a messenger.
But as far as the one that moved up on
the water and separated the water from
the water, then there was another one of
his holy spirits.
Because all angels are spirits. And let
me show you as far as they holy. Go to
one last place. Let's go into Matthew
the 25th chapter.
Let's see where we going to start it at.
I think that's around 31.
25 and 31.
>> Read it when you get there. When the son
of man shall come in his glory and all
the holy angels with him, then shall he
sit upon the throne of his glory.
>> He going to come and all the holy angels
with him. So now if the angels of all
the angels with him is holy and everyone
that are spirit that makes them holy
spirits. Isn't that correct?
>> Right.
>> So now Gabriel just got one job. He got
Satan job. He he was the messenger. The
other angels do other thing like dig man
out of the dust of the ground, separate
the waters from the waters and uh uh and
all the other stuff that the Lord
commanded to do. That's why it said
that's why always before something is
created the Lord the Bible said the Lord
said let there be and whatever he said
let there be the angels bring it into
existence.
>> Right? So now is just a messenger, the
one that separated the water, another
angel. That's all I got to say.
>> Yes, caller. Could we go to one place?
Psalm 103 and 20.
>> Go
>> Psalm 103 and 20. T.
>> Yes, sir. Psalm 103
and verse 20.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Bless the Lord, ye his angels, that
excel in strength, that do his
commandments, harve.
There you go. The angels do his do God's
commandments.
>> What it be say to tell them to do,
that's what they do,
>> right?
All right, sister.
>> That's it. Sister Deborah, time check.
>> Uh, the time is 9:04.
>> And we like to thank everyone who sent
in all those great questions from around
the world. We took joy in answering them
and we pray that you were edified. If
you didn't hear your question answered
tonight, there's no need to resubmit
your question. It will be answered in
the order that it was given and we will
pick up where we left off next week. So,
please join us for next week's Q&A and
be strengthened in the Lord. Brother
Tanzel, close us out.
>> Our Father, which are in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread, and forgive us of our debts as we
forgive our debtors, and lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the
power, and the glory forever. In Jesus
name we pray. Amen.
Amen.